- Previously on Limitless...
- I've been thinking about
지난 이야기
- 생각해봤는데 저격사건 말야
the shooting.
CCTV를 봤는데
피한 것 같았어
I was watching footage of Morra.
It's almost like he dodged.
Do you think he's on NZT?
그 사람도 NZT를 하는걸까?
의원님 코트에요
진짜 코트
Senator's coat. The real one.
혈액에 NZT가 있는
With NZT in the blood.
Everything go smooth?
모두 순조로왔나?
증거보관실 직원이랑
대화하긴 했어요
I had to talk to one guy
in the Evidence unit.
He's dead, Brian.
그가 죽었어
He went to a Chinese restaurant
중국집에 갔는데
거기 주방장은 그 사람
알러지에 대해 알고 있었거든
where the chef knows about his allergy.
Somehow, peanut oil ended up in his entree.
어쩐 일인지 음식에
땅콩 기름이 들어가서
구급차 안에서 죽었어
He died in the ambulance.
누군가가 그를
죽였다고 생각해?
Do you think someone killed him?
누군가 우리가 그 사람이랑
대화하지 않길 바라는 거 같아
I think someone didn't
want us talking to him.
잠복수사
__
세 가지 임무에서의
로맨틱한 장난
_
당신이 내사과에
진술하고 있다는 거 알고 있죠?
You understand you're
giving a statement to IAU
Cyrillus Holdings에 대한
당신의 최근 수사에 대해서 말이죠
about your recent investigation
of Cyrillus Holdings?
그리고 이건 48시간 동안
And that this also includes
the 48-hour period
다른 요원이랑 일했다는 것도 포함합니다
you spent working with another agent.
알았다구요
Look, I get it.
Lucy Church에 대해
말하길 원한다면
You want me to talk about Lucy Church.
하루 죙일 말할 수도 있어요
That works for me; I could talk
about Lucy Church all day long.
어째서 그런거죠?
And why is that exactly?
왜냐하면
Because...
그녀에게서 많이 배웠으니까
I learned a lot from her.
게다가 우리가 만났을 때
제가 좋은 상황이 아니었거든요
Plus, I wasn't in a great place when we met.
지옥에라도 다녀온 사람 같군
You look like you've been through hell.
당신이 한 짓을 알아요
I know what you did.
Jesse Escanso?
증거물실 직원
The Evidence clerk.
누군가가 그의 음식에
He didn't just die because someone
땅콩 기름을 넣어서 죽은게 아니죠
put peanut oil in his Chinese food.
당신 때문에 벌어진 일이죠
You made it happen.
그 말은
나 때문이란 거지
Which means I made it happen.
자네 말이 맞다고 치고
Assuming you're right about any of this...
감사인사라도 하러 온건가?
did you come here to say thank you?
Jesse Escanso 때문에
우리가 하려던 모든 일들이
Jesse Escanso could have,
까발려 질 수 있었고
and would have, exposed everything
그렇게 됐을 거네
that we're trying to do.
그가 만약 "사고"를
당하지 않았다면
And if he hadn't have had... an accident...
지금쯤 자네는
감옥에 있겠지
odds are, you'd be in jail right now.
상관없어요
I don't care.
나는 사람들
죽이고 다니지 않아요!
I don't, I don't go around murdering people.
죽여본 적도 없지
And you haven't.
자넨 나에게 보고를 했네
You gave me a debriefing.
그것에 기반해서 내가
관계됐을 수도, 아닐 수도 있겠지
Based on that, I may or may
not have tended to a loose end.
그게 자네 양심에
무슨 문제라도 되나보지?
What trouble is that to your conscience?
Harris 요원은?
And Agent Harris?
Escanso씨가 죽은 타이밍의 의미를
그녀는 이해했을 거라 생각되네만
Well, I'd imagine the timing
of Mr. Escanso's death
hasn't been lost on her.
Rebecca는 괜찮아요
Rebecca's fine.
그녀 걱정은 하지 마요
You don't have to worry about Rebecca.
어떤 경우라도 그 여자
In any case, she won't be getting
Jesse Escanso에게서
중요한 정보는 얻지 못할 거네
any compromising information
from Jesse Escanso.
상황이 좋지 않았다니?
그게 무슨 말이죠?
You weren't in a great
place? What does that mean?
당신이 걱정할 일은 아니에요
Nothing you need to worry about.
당신이 알고 싶어하던 거
그건 모두
The stuff you want to know, that all started
잠복수사 요원명단이
누출됐을 때 시작됐어요
when the list of undercover agents got out.
Finch!
일어나요!
Get up!
아, Mike!
Mike!
새벽 댓바람부터 뭔 일이야?
What is it, like, 3:00 in the morning?
왜 그러는데?
What do you want?
부장님이 지금 보자십니다
Naz needs you right now.
워싱턴에서 비공식적인
Washington maintains a master list
잠복수사 요원들의
명단 원본을 가지고 있었는데
of every agent working
under nonofficial cover.
2시간 전 누군가
Dupont Circle에 사는
Two hours ago, unknown
persons stole the hard drive
부국장님의 집에서 그걸 훔쳤어
from Deputy Director Rovick's
home in Dupont Circle.
거기에 목록이 담겨있지
The list was on it.
현재 진행 중인 잠복수사가 모두
Every undercover operation we've got going
위태로워져서, 지금 현재
has been compromised, and we're pulling
모두 철수시키는 중이야
all the agents as we speak.
명단이 누출됐나요?
Has the list been leaked?
아뇨 아직
하지만 시간문제겠죠
No, not yet. We only assume
it's a matter of time.
이쪽은 Adrian Vescovi
This is Adrian Vescovi.
이 도시에서 진행되는
잠복수사를 감독하고 있지
He supervises undercover
work in the city, and,
나머지도 설명해주실거야
he will fill you in on the rest.
현재로썬 이 도둑들이
뭘 원하는지 모르겠습니다
At this point, we have no
idea what these thieves want.
이름을 내다 팔 수도 있고
They could be selling these names,
언제든 명단을 공개할 수도 있어요
they could post them publicly at any moment.
현재 22명의 잠복요원이 있는데
We have 22 undercover agents,
그 중 다섯이 소재파악이 안돼요
five of which are unaccounted for.
현재 이들을 찾고 있습니다
Now, obviously, we have our
people looking for them.
당신이 꽤 유능하다고 들었어요
I hear you're quite the problem solver.
당신과 당신 팀이
무슨 짓을 해서라도
I want you and your team
to do everything you can
이 요원들을 찾아주길 바래요
to find these agents.
이게 실종자 명단입니다
These are their names.
들었어? "내" 팀이래
Hear that? He said my team.
나도 들었어
잘 몰라서 그런거야
I heard. He's just ignorant, that's all.
...Liz Collette,
Alex Nellenthal
Lucy Church
Alex Nellenthal and Lucy Church.
네 Lucy 알아요
Yes, I know Lucy.
알았죠...
I knew her.
Um...
Quantico에 같이 있었어요
We were at Quantico together, um...
그러다 어떤 잠복수사 임무 때문에
till she got pulled pre-graduation
먼저 수료했어요
for an undercover assignment.
감옥에서 진행됐다고 들었어요
I heard it was at a prison.
그 후에 또 다른
잠복수사에 투입됐고
Um, and then she went into
another deep undercover position
그렇게 계속 잠복수사만
했다고 들었어요
after that, and then another one after that.
뭐...
So...
그런 사람들이 있죠
That happens to some people.
다른 누군가가 되는 것에
중독되는 거죠
They get addicted to being somebody else.
잠복수사업무에 대해서
제가 아는 거라곤
I mean, the only thing I
know about undercover work
영화에서 본 게 다지만
is what I've seen in the movies,
제가 그 파일들을 뒤졌을 때
but, um, yeah, once I dug into the files,
그 요원들을 찾아내는 게
그리 어렵진 않았어요
finding the agents really wasn't that hard.
잠복한 요원들!
__
Ben Yang 요원은
삼합회에 침투해 있었다
Agent Ben Yang was
deep cover with the Triads.
재밌는 건, 그 요원은
MSG 먹으면 탈 난다는 거
Now, funny enough, the guy
had a sensitivity to MSG.
다행히도 그에 대한 해결책은
Luckily, a lot of people think there's a way
핫식스를 마시면 됨
drink Red Bull.
차이나타운 아파트로 배송되는
I tracked down a bodega-sized
Red Bull shipment
다량의 핫식스를 추적해서
요원을 찾아냈다
to a Chinatown apartment
and found Agent Yang.
Liz Collette 요원이 잠복한 곳은
Agent Liz Collette was working undercover
도난당한 예술품 취급으로
의심받는 갤러리였다
at a blue chip Chelsea gallery
under suspicion of moving stolen art.
예술계 인사는 아무도 안먹는데
Now, here's the thing about
the art world: no one eats.
이 요원은 겁나 쳐드신다는 거
And Agent Collette filed receipts
마지막 임무지에서
청구한 영수증이 산더미였음
from a bunch of burger places
on her last assignment.
이 돼지는 햄버거 가게에서 찾았음
We found her shame-eating at a Shake Shack.
그런 식으로 다 찾고
It went on like that, until the only agent
Lucy Church만 남았음
left unaccounted for was Lucy Church,
부패한 헤지 펀드를 파헤치는
who was in the end stages
of a long assignment
긴 임무의 끝자락에 있었음
at a corrupt hedge fund.
이곳은, 이 도시의 상류층들이
This place apparently cornered the market
돈세탁을 하는 곳이지
on high-end money laundering in the city.
겁나 나쁜 놈들이랑 엮여있어서
It's tied to some very bad people,
아무도 그녀랑 연락할 수 없었음
and no one could get in touch with Lucy.
그래서 내가 이 새벽녘에
Which was how I came to be standing
길 한 복판에
이러고 서있는 거지
in the middle of Ditmars
Boulevard right before dawn,
1968년 무스탱 차량을
찾으면서 말야
looking for a blue 1968 Ford Mustang.
그 이름 알아요
I recognize the name.
얼굴은 모르겠지만
The face does nothing for me.
난 Brian Finch입니다
I'm Brian Finch.
FBI랑 일하죠
I work with the FBI.
당신 신분이 위태로워요
Look, your cover's burnt,
당신 상관이
들어오래요
and your boss, Adrian Vescovi,
says you need to come in.
날 어떻게 찾은거죠?
How did you find me?
과속딱지가 있더군요
You had speeding tickets.
불면증 환자에...
You're an insomniac,
밤늦게 겁나 밟는게
긴장이완에 도움이 되죠
and driving fast late at
night helps you relax.
요원 뱃지가 있으면
I took a bet that once you had a badge,
딱지는 안끊을거라고
생각했어요
you'd just use it to get out of tickets.
사람들을 시켜서
이 도시에서
So, we sent people to the five longest
가장 긴 도로를 찾게 했죠
straightaways in the city.
내가 제일 긴 도로에
나와있는 거구요
I picked the longest one.
이렇게 만났네요
Here we are.
그니까, 누군가
명단을 가져갔는데
All right, so someone took the list,
아직 공개되진 않았단 거죠
but it hasn't been posted publicly yet.
우리가 알기론 아직은요
Yeah, well, not as far as we know.
알려줘서 고마워요
Thanks for the heads-up, Brian Finch.
- 난 안돌아가요
- 왜 이래요!
- I'm not coming in.
- Come on.
아 잠깐만요!
No, wait, wait, wait!
당신 뭐야?
What's your deal?
무슨 말이에요?
What do you mean?
당신 완전 귀요미라
I mean, you're cute enough
꾸미기만 하면
완전 초식남인데
to pull off the whole square-jaw thing,
if you wanted to,
지금 하고 있는 꼬라지는
but you're dressed like you're in line
완전 노숙자잖아요
for the Porta-John at Coachella.
한밤중에 깨워서 그래요
They woke me up in the middle of the night.
그렇다해도
당신이 뭔가 특별하지 않으면
Doesn't matter; the Bureau wouldn't let you
회사에서 그 꼬라지
용납 안할텐데
get away with that unless
you were something special.
그러니...
So...
당신 뭐야?
what's your deal?
전 문제를 해결해요
I solve problems.
풀어야 할 문제라면
나한테 많이 있죠
I am well supplied with those.
몇 분전부터
And, as of a couple minutes ago,
나에겐 그걸 다
해결할 시간이 없으니...
I haven't got a whole lot of
time to sort through them, so...
우왕~ 같이 가자구요?
You want me to come with you?
난 사람 목숨 구하려
이 일을 하는데
I joined the Bureau to save lives.
당신은 뭐 다른 이유가
있을 수 있겠죠
Could be you had different reasons.
지금 나 꼬시는 거 알아요
I know you're manipulating me.
근데 당신은 거기
그러고 서 있죠
And yet you're still standing there.
12시간이나
길 한복판에 서 있었는데
I stood on the road for 12 hours
Lucy 찾았다고
빨리 얘기 좀 해주시지
before somebody told me they found Lucy.
얼굴 뒤집어진거 땜에
불평하는 건 아니에요
I'm not complaining about
the windburn, per se,
전 그저 회사에서
but it would be nice if the Bureau
보상으로 알로에나 줬음 좋겠네요
could reimburse me for some aloe.
??
한글번역 : 번역포럼
Synced by emmasan
www.addic7ed.com
그를 납치했다구요?
Kidnap him?
CJC의 컨설턴트를
납치했냐고 묻는거에요?
You're asking me if I kidnapped
the CJC's consultant?
난 그냥 차문만 열었어요
지가 알아서 탄 거에요
I opened the car door; he got in on his own.
제가 대신 전화걸어줄테니
운전에 집중 좀 할래요?
Hey, do you want me
to dial for you so you
can focus on the road?
상사에게 전화해야 하니
좀 조용히 해줄래요?
I got to call my boss. Try
and be quiet a sec, okay?
Lucy, 지금 스피커 폰으로
Lucy, you're on speakerphone
Pouran 부장과 함께 듣고 있네
with myself and S.A.C. Pouran.
괜찮은가?
Is everything okay?
전 안돌아갑니다
I'm not coming in, Adrian.
아직은요
Not yet.
어.. 그래야 하네
Actually, you are.
난 지금 자네 권한을 박탈할거야
I'm pulling your credentials right now.
누굴 체포하든 효력이 없을 거야
Any arrest you make
will be null and void.
맘대로 하세요
저라면 안그러겠지만
All right, you could do that.
저에겐 Cyrillus Holdings와
50개의 차명계좌를
I mean, I wouldn't, seeing as
I'm the one holding the file
that can tie Cyrillus Holdings to, like,
엮을 수 있는 증거가 있어요
50 criminal counts.
지금 나랑 해보자는 건가?
Don't even start down
this road with me, Lucy.
그 파일 때문이라도
전 빠질 수 없어요
I get pulled in, who's to say
what happens to that file?
Lucy, 여기까지야
Lucy, we're done.
그 사건은 끝이야
This case is over.
그 헤지펀드 잡아넣을
증거는 충분해
We have everything we
need to nail the hedge fund.
아뇨. 기소하기 전에
한 가지가 더 있어요
No, there is one more thing
before we file charges, Adrian,
그게 얼마나
중요한지 아시잖아요
and you know how important it is.
모르는 척 하지 마세요
Don't pretend like you don't.
이틀이야
Two days.
이틀 안에 해결짓고 와
I'm giving you two days
to bring this thing home.
알았어요
Fine.
CJC에서 "어른이"
하나 빌려갈께요
I'm borrowing a man-child from the CJC.
좀 더 나은 꼬라지로
만들어서 돌려드리죠
I'll bring him back in better
shape than I found him.
- 어렵지 않을 거에요
- 이봐! 잠깐!
- Shouldn't be hard.
- Hey, hey, hey, hey!
부장님 전화를 끊은거에요?
Did you just hang up on Naz?
벨트 매, 멋쟁이
Buckle up, handsome.
이틀동안 넌 내꺼야
You're mine for the next two days.
Finch가 현장근무를
하게 돼서 놀랐냐구요?
W-Was I surprised Finch
stayed out in the field?
물론 아니죠
Of course not.
"잠복근무"란 말
들어봤을 겁니다
He probably heard the word "undercover,"
느낌표랑 함께 말이죠
and with that expression
that means exclamation point.
잠복수사라...
Undercover.
나 여기 맘에 들어요
Hey, I like this place.
Cyrillus Holdings 사건은
마무리 단계에 있었어요
I was in the endgame at Cyrillus Holdings...
3년동안 수사했죠
three years of casework.
진짜로 수사는 끝났어요
Technically, the investigation is done.
마지막 한 조각만
있으면 돼요
Just one last piece
needs to fall into place.
- 나 좀 도와줘요
- 그러죠
- Help me out.
- Yeah.
이 마지막 조각을
쫓는 건가요?
So, this last piece,
is that what we're after?
"The Blue Limit"라...
"The Blue Limit""
특급 접대 서비스로 돈 벌어서
Bills itself out as a
premium escort service.
Cyrillus Holdings에서
그 돈을 세탁을 해요
They launder all their cash
through Cyrillus Holdings.
계속 해봐요
Okay, I'm listening.
FBI는 실제로는 그들이
인신매매 조직이라고 믿고 있어요
Good, because the FBI
believes what they really are
is a human trafficking organization.
유럽의 가난한 국가에서
여자들을 잡아들이고 여권을 뺏은 후
They bring in women
from poor countries in Europe,
take their passports,
기본적으론 노예로 파는 거죠
and essentially sell them into slavery.
Cyrillus 수사를 확대한다 해도
But doesn't that mean that they'll just get
그것 때문에 그들이
엮이지는 않을텐데요
rolled up in the larger
investigation of Cyrillus?
Cyrillus Holdings 관련
두 번째 사건
The second
we file a case against Cyrillus Holdings,
그 사건은, Blue Limit랑
that case will encompass
The Blue Limit, and every
other shady business
Cyrillus가 관여한
다른 구린 사업들도 포괄해요
they've ever worked with.
어느 시점부턴가
거기서 일한 여자들이
At which point, the women working there
주요 부채가 되요
will become major liabilities.
Blue Limit에서 그 여자들을
제거한다는 건가요?
You think The Blue Limit would
be inclined to get rid of them?
거기서 문제를 일으킨 여자들은
Women who make trouble there
어떤 방식으로 사라져요
그러니 뭐...
have a way of disappearing,
so, yeah, I do think
크게 보자면 그럴 수 있죠
that could happen on a larger scale.
그 여자들을 구해야돼요
I want to get these women out of there.
여권이 보관된 곳을 찾아내서
I want to find out where
their passports are stashed,
여권을 되찾아서
그들을 집으로 돌려보내야 해요
get them back, so they
can be on their way home
기소되기 전에 말이죠
before charges get filed.
이 새끼들 제대로 된 콩밥
먹여야 돼요
It's not enough these guys
get to go to some golf-farm
white-collar prison.
그 새끼들 노예 매매업자에요
They're slavers.
여자들을 죽인다고요
그것 때문에 잡고 싶은 거에요
They kill women, and I want them for that.
이 자식들은
자기 조직의 기밀을
Now, these guys keep the particulars
조직 내부에 깊숙이
보관하고 있어서
of their organization
pretty close to the belt,
내가 알아낼 수 있는 게
많지 않았어요
so there was only so
much that I could learn.
내부에 정보원이 하나 있었는데
But I had an informant on the inside.
몇 주전, 우리가 조직 구조를
파악하기 시작했을 때
We were just starting to
get a sense of the structure
그녀가 사라졌어요
when she disappeared a few weeks ago,
그녀가 죽임을 당한거죠
which makes me think they had her killed.
난 뭘하면 되죠?
Well, what can I do?
오늘밤, 행사가 있어요
Tonight, The Blue Limit
is holding a benefit,
고위층 고객을 유치하려는 거죠
courting their new high-end clients.
당신은 잠재적 고객으로
참석하는 거에요
You're coming as one of the clients-to-be.
내가 등록해놓을게요
우린 사람들을 홀린 다음에
I will make entry, and we will work the room
여권을 찾으면 되요
and find those passports.
그게 끝?
Just like that?
양복 있어요?
입어보긴 했어요?
Do you have a suit? Have
you ever even worn a suit?
양복 있어요
I got a suit.
빨간색이지만...
It's red.
Okay.
Bergdorf 가게에서
일하는 코디에요
Personal shopper at Bergdorf's.
그가 준비시켜 줄거에요
He'll hook you up.
서둘러요
Chop chop, Brian Finch.
할 일이 많으니
Lots of work to do.
안눙~
Hey there.
사람을 구하려는 중... (엄지 척)
Looking to save lives... thumbs up emoji.
그러려면 NZT가 필요해 (불끈불끈)
Kind of need some NZT to do it...
arm making muscle emoji.
네, Brian이 Lucy와 일하는 동안
Yes, I authorized administering Brian NZT
NZT 사용을 허가했습니다
while he was working with Lucy Church.
그녀의 감독관이 제게
그녀 임무의
Her handler made a strong case
타당성을 제게 설명해주었고
for why she should still be out there.
Brian도 해야할 일과
Brian Finch knew the parameters
하지 말아야 할 일을
알고 있었습니다
of what he was and wasn't supposed to do,
그 안에서 행동할 거라 믿었구요
and I trusted him to act within those.
그리고.. 네, 돌아보면
좀 안일하게 들리겠네요
And, yes, in retrospect, I
realize that may sound naive.
동유럽 여자들이
당신한테 감사할 거야
The women of Eastern Europe thank you.
괜찮아?
You okay?
넋이 나가보이는데
You seem a little distracted.
오늘 아침에 Sands씨
사무실에서 전화가 왔어
I got a call from Jarrod
Sands' office this morning.
그 사람 기억해?
Remember him?
뭐라고?
나 이거 맘에 안드는데?
What? I don't like where this is headed.
Morra 의원 개인경호팀장 말야
He, heads up Senator
Morra's personal security.
알 것 같애
Yeah, I think so.
나중에 좀 보자네?
Well, he wants to meet later.
갈거야?
Are you gonna go?
NZT 때문에 의원님 주변을
쑤시고 다니는데
Well, we're sniffing around
Senator Morra and NZT,
갑자기 난데없이
이런 전화가 온다고?
and all of a sudden
I get this call out of the blue?
그럼.. 가야지
Yeah, I'm gonna go.
The, um...
당신이 입은 양복...
아직 가격표도 안뗐어?
suit that you're wearing, it
still has a tag on the sleeve.
어.. 나도 알아
아직 쇼핑 중이야
Yeah, I know. I'm-I'm still shopping.
나 도와주는 사람한테
I actually told the guy
that was helping me inside
금방 올거라 했거든
that I'd be right back.
괜찮아 보였어요
He looked fine.
멋졌던 것 같아요
Um, good, I guess.
양복이 멋졌거든요
It was a nice suit.
양복 입으면 다 멋져 보이잖아요
Everybody looks better in a suit.
뭐 그딴 걸 물어봐요
Boy, that's a-a weird
question for you to ask me.
초조하거나
좀 이상해보이지 않았어요?
I meant, did Finch
seem nervous or out of sorts?
아뇨
No, no.
자세히 보지 않았거든요
But, I mean, I wasn't looking that closely.
그 날 생각할 게 많아서요
I... I had a lot on my mind that day.
Harris 요원
Special Agent Harris.
와줘서 기쁘네
한 잔 하겠나?
I'm glad you decided to come.
Do you fancy a drink?
아뇨 괜찮습니다
No, I'm good.
여기 괜찮네요
This is a nice place.
의원님께서 자네의
능숙한 일처리에
Senator Morra was impressed
by your deft handling
매우 깊은 인상을 받으셨네
of his attempted assassination.
나도 그랬고
So was I.
도움이 되었다면 다행입니다
Well, I'm glad I could help.
도와줘서 고맙네
And we were glad
for that help.
그리고 사실, 가능하다면
So glad, in fact, that we would
이 관계를 확장시킬 수
있다면 더 기쁘겠네
like to extend the
relationship, if possible.
어떻게 확장하자는 건지?
Extend it how?
의원님과 나는 자네에게
자리를 하나 제안할까 하네
Senator Morra and I would
like to offer you a job.
자리요?
A job?
꽤 짭잘한 자리인데...
A quite lucrative one at that,
의원님 개인경호팀에서
일하는 거지
working on the senator's
private security team.
내가 쪽지에 금액을 적을테니
I'm gonna write a number
on a piece of paper.
자네가 그걸 보면
우리가 얼마나 진지하게
When you see it, I'm
sure you'll be convinced
자네를 스카웃하고 싶은지
about how serious we are
확신할 수 있을걸세
to have you on our team.
당연하지만 모든 특전과
부수입들 포함이라
Naturally, all comes
with perks and privileges
FBI에서 받는 건
하찮아 보일걸세
such as to dwarf anything the
FBI might be able to offer.
말했듯이
As I said,
우린 꽤 진지하네
we're quite serious.
굉장히 인상적인 제안이군요
That's a very impressive offer, Mr. Sands.
생각할 시간을 주시겠습니까?
May I have some time to think about it?
물론이지
Of course.
충분히 생각하게
Take whatever time you need.
감사합니다
Thank you.
Brian
Brian.
먼저 연락하지 말라고 했을텐데
I take it you've been trying to reach me.
잘들으세요
시간이 별로 없어요
Sands, listen to me, I
don't have much time...
진정하게
Relax, Brian.
난 Rebecca를 협박하려는 게 아닐세
I'm not trying to threaten or encroach
in any other way upon Rebecca.
그녀가 더 이상
궁금증을 갖지 못하도록
Since you have failed utterly
설득하는데 자네가
완전히 실패해서
to convince her to stop asking questions,
상황을 개선하러
내가 뛰어든 것 뿐이니까
I've simply stepped in
to smooth things over.
그걸 어떻게 하시는데요?
How are you doing that?
일자리를 제안해네
By offering her a job.
사실 꽤 괜찮은 자리지
Quite an attractive one, in fact.
뭐라구요?
What?
매수하시려는 겁니까?
You're trying to bribe her?
Brian
Brian,
지구 상에서 돈으로
해결 안되는 사람은
I have yet to meet a
human being on this planet
만나보지 못했네
who doesn't have a price.
정말 하고 싶어요?
Sure you're up for this?
물론이죠
Totally.
내가 몇 년을 공들인 거에요
Brian, this is years of my life,
이 일에 엄청 많은
시간을 들였어요
hundreds of hours of work.
잘 할 수 있다니까요
I am absolutely good to go.
알았어요
Okay.
잠복근무!
임무 1
__
이런 역거운 헤지펀트 파티가
처음은 아니지만
It wasn't my first
douchey hedge fund party,
거기 있는 모든 남자들이
but it was the first where
just about every guy there
여자를 사려고 모인
그런 파티는 처음이었다
was there specifically
to buy time with women.
다양한 직업과 흥미를 가진
사람들이 모였다
They ran a pretty wide gamut
of occupations and interests.
투자은행가들은
당연히 거기 있었다
There was the investment
bankers, inevitably.
추론으로 먹고 사는 사람들이니
좋은 인상을 심어주는 일쯤이야
Kind of the easiest to impress,
since they live by speculation.
오픈마켓에서
파생상품 거래는 끝났어요
Because trading on the open market is dead
when it comes to derivatives.
Sharpe 비율도 암시장의 것과
비교도 안되지요
The Sharpe ratio isn't even
comparable with dark pools.
시장의 깊이를 모르면
I mean, no market depth feed,
위험은 가상의 비개체가 되는거죠
[역주: 무슨 말인지.. 경제학은 생략한다]
risk becomes a virtual non-entity.
어서 고객들에게 전화해서
이 얘길 전하세요
And go ahead, call your
clients, take this down.
러시아 조폭 놈들에게는
The Russian oligarch contingent
쉽게 통하진 않았지만
관련있어 보였다
was a tougher nut to crack,
but it seemed relevant
많은 여자들이
동유럽 사람들이었으니까
since a lot of the girls
were Eastern European.
그리고 그럴 가치가 있었다
But it turned out to be worth it,
그렇게 Sergei를
만날 수 있었으니까
since that way I was able to meet Sergei,
Blue Limit의 실세인 그는
The Blue Limit's man in
charge on the ground,
도움이 필요한
자기만의 문제가 있었다
and he had issues of his
own he needed help with.
제가 듣기엔, 당신 조카가
당신 동생의
You know, it sounds to me
like your nephew's just trying
관심을 끌려는 것 같은데요?
to get your brother's attention.
애처럼 운다고?
Cry for help?
그렇죠
딱 그거죠
Exactly, that's exactly right.
이렇게 생각해보세요
I mean, think of it like this, Sergei.
애를 그런 식으로 Ducati에 태워놓으면
[오토바이 브랜드]
You put a kid like that
on a Ducati, he's just gonna ride around
아빠 열받으라고 이리저리 몰고 다니며
사이드 미러 부셔먹겠지만
knocking driver side mirrors
off to get a rise out of Dad.
아빠가 그 오토바이를 치우고
실제로 그 애 말을 들어주면
But if Dad takes away the Ducati
and actually listens to him...
동생이 그런 식으로는
생각 못했을거야
I'm sure he has not thought
of it quite this way.
그렇게 해야죠
Well, he totally should.
Nostrovia
[폴란드 말의 "건배"]
Nostrovia.
Nostrovia
내가 수집할 수 있는
아주 작은 거래들과
With every little exchange,
아주 작은 대화의 단편들로
every snippet of conversation
I was able to pick up,
나는 점점 Blue Limit의 구조를
파악할 수 있었다
I gradually was able to build a sense
of The Blue Limit's hierarchy.
그 모든 아리송한 협박 이메일과
And in every vaguely
threatening e-mail chain,
그 모든 엿들은 규율의 출처에서
every overheard reference to discipline,
계속해서 등장하는
이름이 하나 있었다
there's one name that keeps recurring.
Karl Boorman이에요
Karl Boorman.
고마워요
Thank you.
누군지 알아요
I know the name.
Blue Limit 보안 책임자죠
Head of security for The Blue Limit.
필요하다면 더러운 일들도
감독하더군요
Yeah, he oversees the dirty
work when it needs doing.
그가 모든 직원들의
Stands to reason that
he'd be the person holding
여권을 가지고 있다고
보는게 합리적이에요
the passports of all Blue Limit's workers.
그에게 접근해서
일을 바로잡으면. 짜잔~
Get to him, we make this thing right. Boom.
그래요. 나쁘지 않군요
Okay. Not bad.
"나쁘지 않군요"?
이봐요
"Not bad." Come on.
솔직히 별 기대없이
당신을 데려온건데
Frankly, I didn't bring
you here with high hopes.
완전히 망치진 않았네요
You managed to not totally screw it up
유용한 정보도 좀 얻었으니
나쁘지 않은거죠
and you gained some useful
intel, so, yeah, not bad.
가지 마세요
Please, you stay.
죄송한데, 막 가려던 참이었어요
I'm sorry, we were just about to leave.
Sergei가 보냈어요
Sergei sends me over.
조카일 도와줘서 고맙다구요
To say thank you for helping
with his nephew.
위층에 스위트룸을 마련해뒀어요
There is a suite waiting upstairs.
매우 편안하실 겁니다
Very comfortable.
미안하지만, 일행이 있어요
I'm sorry, I'm with someone.
괜찮아요
That's okay.
Sergei도 알아요
Sergei knows that.
같이 가셔도 되요
She can come, too.
가실거죠?
Yes?
아니 그럼 어떻게 해요?
I mean, what were we supposed to do?
Sergei한테 어떻게 싫다고 해요?
You know, Sergei is not the kind
of guy you want to say no to.
좀... 뻘줌했지만
It was... awkward.
방법을 찾았어요
But we worked something out.
보고 싶어요
I love to watch.
술도 마음껏 마셔요
Feel free to raid the mini-bar.
조아쓰!
Cool.
당연히 그 여자랑 섹스하지 않았어요
Of course, we didn't have
sex with the Russian escort.
그 여자를 바로 돌려보내면
Sergei가 의심할까봐
We just thought it would look suspicious
to send her back to Sergei, so
we waited out the two hours.
2시간을 기다렸어요
다행이도 Irina는
티비를 좋아했어요
Luckily, Irina loves TV.
So You Think You Dance,
[TV 프로그램 이름들]
Yes to the Dress,
Amazing Races,
MythBusters.
마지막 시즌이라
Though, it's their last season.
많이 슬프긴 해요
It's very sad.
목적은 달성했네요
Well, we got what we came for.
Karl Boorman한테
여권이 있어요
Karl Boorman has the passports.
다리 뻗고 잘 수 있겠어요
It's a good night's work.
잠깐 좀 쉬죠
We can relax... a little.
물론 뭐...
다른 게 하고 싶지 않다면...
Unless, of course, you'd rather
spend the time with...
나 리얼리티 쇼
별로 안좋아해요
You know, I'm actually not a
reality TV fan myself, so...
- 진짜요?
- 네
- Really?
- Yeah.
좋아할 것처럼 생겼는데
Seem like the type.
저 여자가 좋아하죠
She really loves it.
저 여자는 운이 좋은 거에요
Well, she's lucky.
특급 상품이라
She's premium product,
인간적인 대우를 받는거죠
so she gets treated with
a degree of humanity.
저 정도로 예쁘지 않은 사람들은...
Some of the others who
maybe aren't so beautiful...
성노예로 인신매매하는 거니까
It's human trafficking for
the purpose of sexual slavery.
티비 보는 것만으로도
저렇게 행복한 거에요
That's why she's so happy to be watching TV.
좋아요, 이젠...
All right, now...
당신 문제에 대해 얘기해봐요
how about you tell me what's bothering you.
문제가 있긴 하지만
Well, there is a situation,
당신한테 말할 순 없어요
but I can't really talk about it.
왜 이러실까
나 아님 누구한테 말하겠어요?
Come on, who can you talk to, if not me?
아무 관련없는 여자
A girl you have absolutely no ties to,
아마도 다신 안볼 여자인데
probably never see me again.
누군가 죽여본 적 있어요?
Have you ever killed someone?
당신은?
Have you?
그런 것 같아요
I think so.
직접 죽인 건 아니지만
제가 한 말 때문에 죽었죠
I didn't actually do it,
it was something I said.
당신이 명령내린 게 아니라면
당신 탓 아니에요
Unless you ordered a hit, that's not on you.
사람들을 통제할 순 없어요
You can't control people.
내 조언은?
My advice?
마음에 두지 마요
Don't dwell on it.
새 사건을 받을 때가
제일 좋을 때 중 하나인데
One of the best feelings
is when I get a new case,
옛 감정들과
그와 관련된 모든 것들을
and I can just leave the old one behind,
다 뒤로 하고 떠나올 수
있기 때문이죠
along with everything that went with it.
그거 참...
That all sounds...
괜찮게 들리네요
kind of okay.
- Good.
- Yeah.
긴장 놓지 마요
I need you in character.
내일도 할 일이 있으니
I got a job for you tomorrow.
잠복수사!
임무 2
__
오만가지 잠복근무
일들이 있잖아요
I mean, there's all kinds of
undercover gigs, you know.
가끔은 정말 죽여주죠
Sometimes it's really badass
파티가 새끈한 언니들
and there's parties and hot girls
뭐 그런 것들이 있고...
가끔은...
and stuff like that, and sometimes...
Finch가 알바생이 됐단 얘길
들었을 때 기분이 어땠냐구요?
Was I sorry
when I heard Finch had to
go back to being a temp?
칸막이 책상에 앉아 하루 종일
서류정리를 해야 했을 때?
To sitting in a cubicle
and filing papers all day?
유감스러웠죠
Yeah.
가슴이 찢어지는 줄 알았어요
My heart bled for him.
Blue Limit은 합법적인
회사처럼 보이고자 했어요
The Blue Limit has a vested interest
in appearing legitimate.
인력이 부족해서
Meaning they get short-staffed,
다른 곳처럼
알바를 고용하는 거죠
they hire a temp, just like anyone else.
그래서 Lucy가 뉴욕의 모든
알바소개소에 전화해서
So Lucy called every temp agency in New York
그 날 아침 Blue Limit에서
알바를 구하는지 확인했어요
to see if they had made
any requests that morning,
그 다음엔 뭐...
and the next thing we knew...
누워서 떡먹기지 뭐
It was like riding a bicycle.
난 꽤 그럴싸한 알바생이었다
I was a very convincing temp.
약을 한 알 더 먹자
너무 그럴싸해졌지
And after one more NZT
pill, maybe too convincing.
자료 입력 따위의
일을 하는 사람들이
It was a bet that nobody
working low-level data entry
어젯밤 VIP 파티에 왔을리 없겠지만
was at the VIP party last night,
도박을 해보기로 했지
but we were willing to take those odds.
입력할 자료가 있는 한
아무도 날 귀찮게 하지 않았다
And as long as I had data to
enter, nobody bothered me.
그래서 난 이상한 점들을
주시할 수 있었다
And I could keep an eye
out for anything unusual.
양복입은 저 남자처럼...
Like that guy in the suit,
그리고 그가 들어간
저 문처럼...
and that secure door he
keeps disappearing behind.
보안이란게, 물론
상대적인 거라서
Though security is a
relative term, of course.
자세히 들어보면
버튼이 내는 소리들이
If you listen carefully, every key makes
약간씩 다르다는 걸 알 수 있지
a slightly different
sound when you press it.
노래를 배우는 것처럼
It's kind of like learning a song.
저거 보이지?
벌써 점심시간이란 말이지
And would you look at that?
It's already time for lunch.
여기에 뭘 숨긴걸까?
What are they hiding in here?
어랏? 생각보다 보안에 신경 좀 썼군
Guess it's a little
more secure than I thought.
유투브 짤 몇 개만 보면
But with a little help from a few
instructional videos on YouTube,
금고 따는거야 뭐...
I was able to crack the safes.
처음 두 개는 별 볼일 없지만
First two safes weren't much help,
마지막 금고는...
but on the last one...
대 to the 박!
Jackpot.
도망이라도 치시나?
Going on the lam?
내가 뭐... Svetlana 라는
여자라면 그럴지도?
If I were a Latvian brunette
by the name of... Svetlana.
이름 참 맘에 드네
I do like that name.
그럼 대체 뭐하는거에요?
What exactly are you doing, then?
보시다시피
여권을 다 찾았어요
Well, I got all the passports
back, as you can see.
이런 거 쯤이야 뭐...
You're welcome, by the way.
돈 말이에요
I meant with the cash.
다음 단계를 생각해봤죠
Well, I started thinking about what's next.
우린 이 여자들이 빠져나와
집으로 가게 도우려는 거잖아요
I mean, we're helping all these women
get out and go home,
하지만 뭐 땜에?
but to what?
그들 대부분 여기 머무는 이유가
A lot of them only ended up here because
고향보단 여기가 더 나을 거라
생각하기 때문이죠
they thought it would be better
than what they had before.
그래서 이번엔 확실히
So, I want to make sure
좀 더 많은 선택지를 주고 싶어요
they have more options this time.
수 천 달러나 되네요
This is thousands of dollars.
이 돈이 다 어디서 났어요?
Where did you get this money?
여권 되찾는 게 얼마 안걸려서
I mean, getting the passports
back didn't take very long,
경마장에 들렀죠
so I stopped by the horse races.
경주마에 대해 좀 읽어보고
운도 좋아서
I read up on a few of the
ponies, got a little lucky,
돈 좀 따서 집으로 온거에요
and went home with a bit of cash.
이 정도면 자기 발로
Just a little something to help
집으로 가겠죠
get them back on their feet.
다음 번엔 강원랜드에 같이 가요
Remind me to take you to Vegas next time.
더 알아낸게 있어요
That's not all I found, though.
여권과 함께
With the passports,
이 장부들도 있었어요
there were all these ledgers.
대부분은 지루한
회계 관련 일들이죠
Now, it's mostly really
boring accounting stuff.
그런데...
Except...
"에델바이스" 알아요?
do you know anything about "Edelweiss"?
고딩 때 "사운드 오브 뮤직"
공연을 했어요
I was in The Sound of Music in high school.
글쿤여
Okay, so,
"에델바이스"는 무슨 암호명 같아요
"Edelweiss" seems to be
some kind of code name.
장부에 계속 등장하는데
It's all over the place in these ledgers,
이게 뭘 가리키는지 모르지만
and whoever or whatever it is,
Blue Limit으로부터
돈을 받고 있었어요
it was getting payouts from The Blue Limit,
겁나 교묘하고
복잡하게 꼬아놔서
designed specifically to be
crazy complicated and nearly...
추적 못하도록...
Impossible to trace.
그르쳐
Exactly.
에델바이스를 찾아야 해요
We need to find Edelweiss.
나도 딱 그 생각을 했어요
I had the exact same thought.
여기가 Queens 지역이고...
이게 바로
This is Queens, and this...
에델바이스죠
is Edelweiss.
공식적인 이름은
"독일 환대 연맹"인데
Whose official name of record is
the German Hospitality League,
아마도 무슨 다문화
친선 모임 같은데
supposedly some
cross-cultural goodwill club.
여기가 바로 그 의심스러운 기금에서
And the recipient of record for payouts
돈을 수령하는 곳으로
기록되어 있죠
from the magical mystery fund.
얼굴마담이네요
That's a front.
여기서 그리 멀지 않네요
This place is less than a mile from here.
내일 아침 거길 가보면
And I figure that if we go
over there in the morning,
Blue Limit을 위해 여자들을
죽인 놈들을 찾을 수 있겠죠
we'll find whoever's been killing the women
for The Blue Limit.
이런 반응을 기대한게 아닌데?
That wasn't the reaction I expected.
뭐...
Well, I was...
대단히 인상적이군요
really impressed.
제가 조사한 게?
아니면 키스가?
With the research or with the kiss?
그래서요?
And?
그래서라뇨?
And what?
그냥 같이 좀 웃고...
별 일 없었어요
No, we had some laughs, no big deal.
아니 진짜...
S-Seriously, I-I don't...
무슨 얘기를 원하시는지
모르겠네
I don't know what you want me to say.
그...그게... 다에요
That's-that's the end
of the story. We just...
??
죄송한데...
어디까지 했었죠?
I'm sorry, where were we?
잠깐 딴 생각을 했어요
I lost my train of thought a little bit.
이틀 간의 완전 전문적인
공조 수사를 통해
So, after two days of strictly
professional collaboration,
Blue Limit을 위해
Lucy의 정보원을 포함한,
we had the address of the
guy The Blue Limit was paying
여자들을 살해한 남자의
주소를 얻게 되었죠
to murder women, including Lucy's source,
그런데 문제가 생겼어요
but we ran into a problem.
어쩐 일이야?
Hey.
48시간 다 됐어
복귀할 시간이야
48 hours are up.
It's time to come home.
뭐라고?
What?
당신 버려질 거야
They're cutting you off.
무슨 소리야 그게?
Wait, what do you mean?
당신 돌아오기 전까진
조제실에서 더 이상 NZT 안준데
Dispensary isn't issuing any
more NZT until you come back.
당신이 해줄 일이 하나 더 있어요
I need you for one more thing.
이 일 끝장을 보고 싶은데
Look, I really want to
see this case through.
아직 돌아갈 수 없어
I'm not ready to come back in.
당신 눈맞았구나?
You hooked up, didn't you?
Lucy랑 당신...
You and Lucy.
뭐라고?
What?
아냐... 그런거...
No, that's... Come on.
텐트치고 그러지 않았어
[남성의 발기]
We didn't... Bollywood.
무슨... 미친...
That's crazy.
왜 그런 생각을 하는건데?
Why would you even suggest that?
뭐 상관없어
Fine, I don't even care.
약없이 일하고 싶으면
You want to work the case off NZT,
그렇게 해
work the case off NZT.
간섭 안할테니
I'll even run interference,
하지만 부장님께는
당신이 직접 설명해
but you're the one that
has to answer to Naz.
진짜 고마워
그리고 우리...
Thank you, seriously. And we didn't...
그래서...
다음 임무는 뭐지?
All right, what's this assignment?
잠복근무!
임무 3
__
잠깐만요
이 부분이 납치랑 관련된 부분인가요?
Hold on. Is this the
part with the kidnapping?
가벼운 납치에요
Kidnapping-light, okay.
뭐 "납치 비스므리"하다고
하셔도 돼요
It's, like, kidnapping adjacent,
if you can even call it that,
어쨋든 그런 건 아니니까
which you can't, by the way,
납치당한 쪽이 결국엔
because the kidnapped
party ultimately agreed
납치 계획에 동의했거든요
to the arrangement.
Lucy의 정보원을
살해한 놈을 찾기 위해
In order to discover
who killed Lucy's informant,
누가 거기서 일했는지 알아야했다
we needed to know who worked there.
나에겐 NZT가 없으니
Now, I didn't have any NZT,
도착 한 시간전에 미리
so about an hour prior to my arrival,
Everywhere의 해커 친구들에게
I had my hacker buds at Everywhere
DoS 바이러스를
dump a Denial-of-Service virus
그 곳 서버에 심어달라고 했다
onto the German Hospitality League server
그러면 Wi-Fi가 뻑날테고
to crash its Wi-Fi,
서비스센터에
전화할 수 밖에 없지
forcing a call for outsidetech support.
뭐 사소한 납치같은게
일어나긴 했지만...
And, yes, a little minor-league
kidnapping might have ensued.
뭐야!
Hey!
Lucy가 AS 직원에게
돈 몇 푼이랑
Lucy hooked up the Data dude
with a couple of hundred bucks
애슐리 식사권을 쥐어줬으니
and a gift card for a
taco place in Greenpoint.
그는 문제없을 거다
He'll be all right.
공돌이가 그런 곳을
언제 가보겠어
Tech nerds love guacamole.
사진이랑 이름 같은 것만 얻어내면
All I had to do was get
a picture, maybe a name,
사건은 성립하니까
and we could build a case.
약같은 건 필요없었지
I didn't need a pill for that.
하지만 긴장되는 일이긴 하지
Still, it's kind of nerve-wracking.
냉혈한 살인마가
여기서 일하는데...
There is a stone-cold killer working here.
안녕하세요
Hi-ya.
Wi-Fi 때문에 오신거죠?
You here about the Wi-Fi?
어디... 봅시다
Okay, let's see here.
옛날 방식으로 설치됐네요
You got the old setup.
이거지...
Here we go.
이런 일 해보신 거 맞아요?
You sure you've done this before?
아 그럼요!
매번 하는 일인데요
Yeah, yeah, yeah,
I do this all the time.
자면서도 할 수 있어요
I could honestly do this... in my sleep.
제가 자면서 걷거든요
'Cause I sleepwalk, sometimes, so...
그걸... 몽유병이라고 하죠
It's-it's called, um... somnambulism.
최대한 시간을 끌었지만
I stalled for as long as I could.
안내원은 자기 사장에 대해
얘기하지 않았다
I couldn't get the receptionist
to talk about her boss.
거의 오지 않는다는 말만 들었다
She just said he was rarely there.
잘 돼가요?
Any luck?
어... 저기... 있죠...
You know what,
제 생각엔 말이죠.. 저기...
I think you guys might need a new,
그 뭐냐.. 토끼 귀같이 생긴...
새 라우터가 필요해요
that-that rabbit ear thing,
what's it called? Router?
저기요.. 아무래도
당신 회사에 전화해서
Hey, maybe I'd better call your office
다른 사람을 보내달라고 할까봐요
to see if they can send along someone
좀 더 능력있는 사람으로요...
more, confident.
어...
네... 뭐.. 그러세요
I mean, o-okay.
뭐... 알겠어요
You know, that's... I understand.
저도 매번
최선을 다하긴 하는데...
Try to give 110% every time.
이렇게 돼서 정말 죄송합니다
I do apologize about this.
뭐 그게...
It's just, you know,
가끔은 문제가 생각보다
sometimes these things are
a little more complicated
훨씬 복잡해서요
than they seem.
어... 제가 최선을
Just tell them, um...
다했다는 건 말씀해주세요
I gave it my all.
잡지에서 이름을 알아냈지만
The magazine gave me a name.
From there, it wasn't
사진을 얻는 건 힘들 거다
gonna be hard to get a picture of the guy.
Lucy는 꼭지가 돌겠지
Lucy is gonna be psyched.
개자식
Son of a bitch.
우리가 확인한 바로는
Our source
confirms that the list of
현재 잠복근무 중인
FBI 요원의 명단이
active undercover agents
within the FBI was exposed
해킹을 당했을 때
이미 유출되어
when computer hackers
stole the intelligence,
현재 암시장에서 거래되고 있습니다
and began horse trading on the black market.
난 끝났어
I'm burned.
진짜로
For real.
알아요
I know.
아니, 당신은 몰라
No, you don't.
이것 때문에
Gudmund에 대한
Because of this, the claim
against The Blue Limit
수사를 시작하기도 전에
will go public before we
can even build a case
Blue Limit에 대한
혐의가 알려지겠죠
against Gudmund Friedrich.
그 때쯤이면 그는
종적을 감출 거에요
And by then, he'll be in the wind.
하지만 Cyrillus Holdings는
끝장낼 수 있잖아요
You can still bring down Cyrillus Holdings.
접대 서비스로 엮으면...
The escort service will get rolled in...
그 새끼가 저 밖에 있다고요
There's a guy out there.
그 새끼가 내 정보원을 쏴죽이고
He pulled the trigger on my informant,
다른 수많은 여자도 죽였어요
a bunch of other women.
그 새끼를 이렇게 놓칠 순 없어
There's no way he walks from this.
FBI보다 우리가 먼저 잡아야 해요
We have to get Friedrich
before the FBI does.
어떻게 하려구요?
What are you going to do?
가요
We got to go.
여기는 더 이상 안전하지 않아요
It's not safe here anymore.
아뇨, 저는 Brian을 데리러
가지 않았습니다
No, I did not drive out
personally to bring Brian in.
그런 말이 듣고 싶으시겠지만
That seems to be what you're getting at.
그냥 물어본 겁니다
Just asking questions.
에델바이스에서의 일은
재앙이었어요
What happened at Edelweiss was a disaster.
재앙이라구요?
A disaster?
다른 말로 표현하실 수도
있을텐데요?
I could think of a few words
I would use before that one.
전 바빴어요
사건도 있었고
I was busy. I had casework.
이 사건과 관련없는
회의에도 참석해야 했구요
I had a meeting to get
to, totally unrelated.
저에게 관심가져 주셔서
감사합니다. 정말로요
I appreciate your interest
in me, sincerely, and...
제가 제시하는 조건을
받아주신다면
if you're willing to accept
the terms of my counter,
계약하겠습니다
I think we can wrap this up.
그 조건이란게...?
And the terms are?
"당신은 얼마에 계약했나요?"
__
조사를 좀 해봤죠
I did some research.
의원님 밑에서 일하시기 전
Before you went to work for Senator Morra,
당신 이력서에 몇 군데
이상한 점이 있더군요
there were a few holes
in your resume.
외교부에서 근무하고
아프리카에서 6개월...
A diplomatic posting here,
six months in Africa there.
하지만 당신 MI-6였어요
[영국 군정보부 요원]
But you were MI-6.
의원님께 얼마를 받고
SIS를 나온 건가요? [영국 비밀정보부]
How much did Morra pay to
take you away from the SIS?
이미 그 정도를 알아냈다면
If you already learned this much...
그 질문에 대한 답을
구할 수 없다는 것도 알겠군
you know there's no chance
I can answer that question.
그게 지금 이 협상과
무슨 관련이 있는지도 모르겠고
And I hardly see what it has to
do with the present negotiation.
이건 협상이 아니죠
This isn't a negotiation.
둘 중 하나가 벌어지는 거죠
One of two things is happening.
진짜로 제게 관심이 있는 거라면
Either you're genuinely interested in me,
그렇다면
in which case,
고맙지만 사양하겠어요
thanks, but no thanks.
난 나쁜 놈들 잡는게 좋아요
I like catching the bad guy.
제 적성이랄까?
Kind of my thing.
그렇다면 두 번째 가능성은?
And the second possibility?
FBI의 누군가에게서
제가 가진 궁금증에 대해 들으신거죠
Someone at the FBI has
been telling you about
the questions I've been asking.
만약 의원님이
NZT를 사용하고 계신다면...?
If Senator Morra is using NZT...
2년 전, 그 약들이
자취를 감춘 일과
if he is connected to the
purges that wiped the pills
의원님이 관련이 있다면...?
off the streets two years ago,
그렇게 매수하는 걸로는
it's gonna take more than a buyout
절 막을 수 없을 겁니다
to keep me from the truth.
자네 태도가 매우 단호한데...
That's a strong position you're staking out.
확실한 증거를 가지고
그런 소리를 하는 거겠지?
I take it you've got concrete
evidence to back those claims.
이제 시작일 뿐입니다
I am just getting started.
Friedrich가 나타날까요?
Do you think Friedrich will show?
안내원에게
I told his receptionist
1시간 후에 Blue Limit을
덮칠거라 했어요
we're raiding The Blue Limit in an hour.
여기가 돈줄인게 확실하니까
I guarantee he keeps a cash horde here.
그가 여길 오거나
그녀가 사장에게 가겠죠
He'll come here or she'll go to him.
그러고 나면?
And then what?
구매자 목록이 우리한테 있으니
We got the list of the payouts.
겁을 먹을지도 몰라요
Let's see how easy he scares.
그 놈이 몸통이든 하수인이든
He's either the guy or he's
the guy leading to the guy,
나한테 불게 되겠죠
but one way or another,
he's gonna talk to me.
갑자기 든 생각인데
It's just hitting me.
내 얼굴이 까발려졌잖아요
My face is out there.
다시는 잠복수사를 못하겠죠
I can never go undercover again.
난 이제 끝났어요
My career's dead.
FBI가 다른 일을 주지 않겠어요?
Won't the FBI give you another job?
내가 Lucy Church로
일하길 원했다면
If I wanted to work as Lucy Church,
예전에 그렇게 했겠죠
I would've done that a long time ago.
그녀로 돌아가는 게
가능할지나 모르겠어요
I don't even know if I
can go back to being her.
"그녀"가 아니에요
It's not her.
당신이지
It's you.
그럴지도
I guess.
저 놈이에요
That's him.
네
Yup.
지원요청 할까요?
Do you want to call for backup?
뭐 때문에요?
그럴 시간 없어요
For what? We don't have
enough to arrest him.
워~워~
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
그 놈이 겁을 안먹으면?
What if you can't scare him into a deal?
CJC로 돌아가요
You should go back to the CJC, Finch.
무슨!
지금은 안돼죠
No, no way, not now.
저기서 무슨 일이
벌어질지 몰라요
I have no idea how it's gonna
go down in there, Brian.
피곤해보이고
You look tired.
총기(반짝임)도 사라지고
I can tell. You've lost
your... spark or something,
그리고 이 자식 위험한 놈이에요
and this guy is really dangerous.
당신 말이 맞긴 한데
Look, you're not wrong, okay?
당신 혼자 가게 둘 순 없어요
But I'm not letting you go in there alone.
그러니 날 데려가던가
아니면
So either take me or I call it in
지원요청해서 FBI가
여기에 득시글거리게 하던가
and the FBI swarms this
place, and that's that.
사격 훈련은 받았죠?
You've taken a TAC course, yeah?
받았어요
I've had training.
총이 장전되어 있으니
You're loaded, one in the chamber.
곤경에 처하면
어떻게 하는지 알죠?
You know what to do if we get into trouble.
안전장치는 어디에...?
Is there a safety on the...?
당신 손이 안전장치에요
Safety's your finger.
알았어요
Right.
저기... Brian...
And, Brian...
난 쏘지 마요
don't shoot me.
가죠
Let's go.
Blue Limit랑 상의해봤는데
I consult with The Blue Limit.
이건 아무 것도 증명 못해
This is proof of nothing.
이건 시작에 불과해
This is just the point of the spear.
매우 간단하지
This will be easy.
너는 Blue Limit과의
You describe your dealings
인신매매 거래내역을 진술하고
with The Blue Limit's trafficking operation.
Karl Boorman과 Sergei를
우리에게 넘겨
You give us Karl Boorman and Sergei,
그러면 너를
어느 정도 선처해줄거야
and you can count on a
certain measure of leniency.
그리고 진짜로 나는
And believe me, I have enough evidence
널 평생 감옥에 썩게할
증거도 충분히 갖고 있어
to bury your ass for the rest of your life.
자신만만하시군
You are very convincing.
놀랍지도 않지
Hardly surprising.
그리 오래 거짓말을 해왔는데
You've been lying for years.
간단한 양자택일이야
It's a simple binary choice.
협조하든가
평생 감옥에서 썩든가
A little cooperation or the
rest of your life in prison.
그런 증거가 있었다면
이미 난 체포됐겠지
If you had what you say,
I'd already be under arrest.
이거 가지곤 어림없지
You'd have brought more than this...
넌 머리나 잘라
haircut for backup.
Blue Limit은 끝장나겠지만
The Blue Limit will fall,
난 거기서 일하지 않아
but I do not work at The Blue Limit.
노력은 가상하지만
You tried.
넌 실패했어
You failed.
집에나 가
Go home.
Lucy, 뭐하는거에요?
Lucy, what are you doing?
이제 내가 양자택일을 할 차례군
Now it's my turn to make
a simple binary choice.
널 잡아들이고 운에 맡기느냐
I bring your ass in and I take my chances,
아니면 지금 이 자리에서
정의를 실현하느냐
or I serve justice right here, right now.
어느 쪽으로 기울고 있는지
쉽게 알겠지?
Probably not too hard to figure
out which way I'm leaning.
??
Lucy, 제발
이러지 마요
Lucy, come on, you don't want to do this.
너 크게 실수하는 거야
You are so very wrong about that.
이래서 여기 오지 말라고 한 거에요
This is why you shouldn't have come, Brian.
- 이걸 보면 안됐어요
- 저기요?
- You shouldn't see this.
- You know what?
이래서 내가
여기 있어야 하는 거에요
Then that's exactly why I should be here.
당신이 이러면
모든 게 끝이에요
Because if you do this, it's over.
당신 감옥에 갈 거라고
You go to prison.
당신만 조용하면 돼요
Only if you tell.
말할 거에요
I will tell.
당신 경력, 당신의 삶
And that's your career and your life
이번 사건에서 당신이 도와준
그 모든 여자들
and all the women that
you helped on this case.
뭐 때문에?
이 자식 때문에?
And for what? For him?
Listen, I can prove that Friedrich
내가 증명할 수 있어요
Friedrich이 Blue Limit의
접대원들과 관련있다는 거
is tied to The Blue Limit's escorts.
- 어떻게?
- 지금은 몰라요
- How?
- I don't know yet.
시간이 필요해요
하지만 잘 끝날 거에요
I still need time, but this can end well.
내 사건이니...
내가 끝낼 거에요
As far as I'm concerned, it's just about to.
Lucy, 난 FBI에 말해야 할 건데
Lucy, I'm gonna have to tell the FBI,
나도 죽이고
unless you're gonna kill me, too,
안내원도 죽이고
and the receptionist,
관련된 사람 다 죽일 건가요?
and anyone else who might happen along.
이 자식 보석으로 풀려나면
Dusseldorf 비행기를 바로 탈 거고
If he makes bail, he'll be on
the next plane to Dusseldorf
그럼 다시는 못봐요
and we'll never see him again.
그런 꼴 못봐요
To hell with that.
어제 그런 얘기했었죠
이 일과 관련된 사람들이
Yesterday, were talking about how people die
어떻게 죽어나갔는지...
그리고 그건 당신 책임 아니라고
in this line of work and
you're not responsible,
비록 그렇게 느껴지더라도 말이죠
even though you can't help
but feel a part of it.
근데 당신이 방아쇠를 당기면
이건 당신 책임이 되는 거에요
If you pull this trigger,
you are responsible,
빼도박도 못하는 사실이 된다구요
and you can't get away from that.
당신은 살인자가 되는 거에요
영원히
That is you.
That is you forever.
잘 들어요
당신이 원하는데로
Listen to me, I will back up
무슨 얘기든 지어낼테니
이 놈 죽이지 마요
any story you want, but not if you kill him.
안 그러면 난 못해요
안할 거에요
I can't do that. I won't do that.
알았어요
Fine.
무슨 짓이에요!
What did you do?
여기서 걸어나가지 못하게요
Not walking out of here now.
좋아, 우리 할 일이 있어
All right, we got work to do, boys.
사실 난 그 모든 것을
Actually, I was able to prove
그의 수술이 끝나기 전에 이미
증명할 수 있었어요
the whole thing even before
Friedrich got out of surgery.
Cyrillus Holdings와
Blue Limit의
And once they started making arrests
관련자 체포가 시작되자
at Cyrillus Holdings and The Blue Limit,
수많은 구매자들이
면죄부를 댓가로
we found tons of takers
willing to corroborate
Friedrich의 역할을
밝히는데 협조해주었죠
Friedrich's role in exchange for immunity.
헤지펀드의 수많은
남자들을 심문해보면
I mean, you haven't seen a lack of backbone
진짜 찌질한 못난이들이
어떤 건지 알게 될 겁니다
until you've questioned a bunch
of guys from a hedge fund.
솔직히 난
어떻게 해야될지 모르겠네
Frankly, I-I'm at a total loss.
자넬 구금해야 하는지
아니면 그냥
I-I don't know whether
to take you into custody
정의구현 방해를 이유로
자넬 해고해야 하는지 모르겠네
or simply fire you for
obstruction of justice.
세 건의 일급 살인 혐의로
Gudmund Friedrich를 잡았잖아요
You have Gudmund Friedrich on
three counts of Murder One.
명령 불복종에 대한 불만이
이번이 처음이 아니야
Lucy, this isn't the first
complaint of insubordination.
잠복수사에선
결과가 수단을 정당화해주죠
In undercover work, the
ends justify the means.
그렇지 않다면
정당화할 방법을 찾으셔야죠
And if they don't, you
find a way to justify them.
저에게 그렇게 가르치셨잖아요
Isn't that what you taught me?
Brian에게 장전된 무기를
지급한게 사실인가?
Is it true you gave Brian
Finch a loaded firearm?
자네 대체 무슨 생각이었나?
What the hell were you thinking?
꽤 괜찮은 파트너라고 생각했는데요?
I was thinking I had a pretty good partner.
그가 죽는 건 보고싶지 않았습니다
Didn't want to see him get killed.
자네가 거침없이 자기를 쐈다는
Friedrich의 이야기는?
And Friedrich's story
about Lucy shooting him
in cold blood?
여자들 죽이는게 직업인 놈입니다
I mean, this is a guy who
murders women for a living.
누가 그 말을 믿겠어요?
Who you gonna believe?
이건 확실히 종결된 게 아니야
Well, this certainly isn't over.
내사과에서
전면적인 조사가 있을 거야
There will be a full after-incident
investigation with IAU.
그러니 다들 녹화 준비하라고
So, everyone, get ready for camera.
사전에 조사한 바에 따르면
The preliminary investigation
Church 요원의 총구가 정확히
indicates the barrel of
Agent Church's pistol
Friedrich의 무릎을
겨냥한 것으로 나오는데
was pressed directly
against Friedrich's knee.
몸싸움을 하는 과정에
It seems odd that that would happen
그런 일이 일어났다는 건
좀 이상하군요
during the course of a struggle.
음... Lucy는...
Well, Lucy, or, um...
Church 요원이라 해야겠죠
Agent Church, rather,
저를 위험에 처하게 했습니다
she put me in harm's way.
제가 죽을 수도 있었단 거죠
Like, I could've been killed.
제가 왜 그녀를 위해
거짓말을 하겠습니까?
What possible reason would
I have to lie for her?
이봐요
Hey.
당신.. 진심이에요?
You're... Seriously?
"나중에 봐요"라고 썼잖아요
I wrote, "See ya later."
난 포스트잇을 쿨한 일에 사용하는데
You know, I always use sticky notes
to build really cool stuff,
이제 당신 때문에 다 망쳤어요
and now you have tainted them forever
당신의 그... 슬픔 때문에
with your sad... sadness.
알았어요
Okay.
"나중에"라고 했지
다시 보지 말자곤 안했어요
It says, "later," not "never."
그러니...
또 봐요
So... later.
Lucy, 저기...
Lucy, um...
나에 대해 해줄 말이 있어요
I got to tell you something about me.
- 알았죠?
- 상관없어요
- All right?
- I don't care.
뭐라구요?
You what?
나도 알아요. 약 때문이죠
복잡한 일이고...
I know. There's a drug, it's complicated.
상관없어요
I don't care.
약을 했든 안했든
난 당신의 본 모습을 아니까
Drug or no drug, I know who you are.
난 그런 당신이 좋아요
I like who you are.
나처럼 되진 마요
I don't want you to become like me.
모든 걸 구분짓는 그런 사람...
Compartmentalizing everything.
자기가 만나보지도 못할
수 많은 여자들을 위해서
It'd be a shame, stripping away pieces
오후 내내 경마게임을 하는
그런 남자를
of the kind of guy who spends an afternoon
속속들이 까보는 건
playing the ponies for a bunch of women
좀 그렇잖아요
he's never even met.
그게 다인가요?
Is it done?
이게 대체 뭐야?
What is this crap?
Paper plane이잖아
[칵테일 이름]
Paper plane.
그러시던가
You say so.
Keener?
끝냈어
It's done.
전부 다 설치했어
Full treatment.
잠꼬대로 장 볼 거리를 속삭인데도
If she whispers her
grocery list in her sleep
오이가 몇 개 필요한지도
알 수 있을 거야
with the radio on, you'll know
how many cucumbers she needs.
그 여자...
She...
낯이 익던데...
she looked familiar.
자네는 그녀의 아버지를 아니까
You knew her father.
다른 옵션은 어떻게 됐어?
What about the other option?
나한테도 잠깐의 기회가 주어지나?
I see a window of opportunity?
가지게
Take it.
Synced by emmasan
www.addic7ed.com
Honey Boo Boo,
Who Marries the Millionaire,
Dance Mom,
Bachelor, Bachelorette.
Real Housewives에 나온
그 여자 알아요?
You know that lady from Real Housewives?
친구를 만들려고 나온게
아니라고 했어요
She said she wasn't there to make friends,
근데 있잖아요
but you know what?
그 여자...
친구 사귀려고 나온 것 같아요
I think she was there to make friends.
외로운 사람 같았거든요
I think she's a very lonely person.